□+1 (734) 496-1803 | 🗷 jwnchung@umich.edu | 🏕 jaewonchung.me | 🖸 jaywonchung | 🛅 jae-won-chung-cs

Summary_

I am a fourth year PhD candidate in CSE at the University of Michigan, working with <u>Professor Mosharaf Chowdhury</u>. I build **efficient software systems for deep learning**, with a recent focus on the efficient management of not only time, but also energy. I lead the <u>ML Energy initiative</u> and created <u>Zeus</u>, an open-source library for deep learning energy measurement and optimization.

Education

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2021 - present

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep 2021 - Apr 2023

Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Mar 2015 - Aug 2021

GPA: 4.04/4.3 (overall) 4.15/4.3 (major), Summa Cum Laude. Period includes two years of military service.

Publications

- **Perseus: Reducing Energy Bloat in Large Model Training,** <u>Jae-Won Chung,</u> Yile Gu, Insu Jang, Luoxi Meng, Nikhil Bansal, Mosharaf Chowdhury, **SOSP**, 2024 (Acceptance rate = 17.34%)
- Toward Cross-Layer Energy Optimizations in AI Systems, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Nishil Talati, and Mosharaf Chowdhury, **DOE ASCR Energy- Efficient Computing for Science Workshop**, 2024
- Andes: Defining and Enhancing Quality-of-Experience in LLM-Based Text Streaming Services, Jiachen Liu, Zhiyu Wu, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Fan Lai, Myungjin Lee, Mosharaf Chowdhury, Preprint, 2024
- Chasing Low-Carbon Electricity for Practical and Sustainable DNN Training, Zhenning Yang, Luoxi Meng, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Mosharaf Chowdhury, ICLR Workshop: Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning, 2023
- Zeus: Understanding and Optimizing GPU Energy Consumption of DNN Training, Jie You*, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>*, Mosharaf Chowdhury, Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2023 (Acceptance rate = 18.38%)
- ShadowTutor: Distributed Partial Distillation for Mobile Video DNN Inference, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Jae-Yun Kim, Soo-Mook Moon, International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP), 2020 (Acceptance rate = 28.99%)
- * Equal contribution

Research Experience _____

Energy-Efficient Systems for Machine Learning

SymbioticLab, UMich

ADVISOR: MOSHARAF CHOWDHURY

Sep 2021 - Present

- <u>Zeus</u>: Discovered the trade-off between DNN training time and energy. Designed a Multi-Armed Bandit solution for time-energy optimization.
- · Perseus: A system for energy-efficient large model training (e.g., LLM). Cuts up to 30% energy without slowdown. Open-sourced as part of Zeus.
- <u>ML.ENERGY Leaderboard & Colosseum</u>: The first systematic benchmark and interactive comparison service for GenAI energy consumption, including LLMs, Multimodal LLMs, and Diffusion models.

Software Systems for Machine Learning

Software Platform Lab, SNU

Advisor: Byung-Gon Chun

Apr 2020 - Jun 2021

• Crane: A GPU cluster manager for AutoML workloads. Built a Kubernetes backend that scaled to 288 GPUs. Contributed core features such as automatic bootstrapping on Docker Swarm and Kubernetes and log streaming through the EFK (Elasticsearch - Fluent Bit - Kibana) stack.

Online Model Specialization for Edge Video DNN Inference

Virtual Machine and Optimization Lab, SNU

ADVISOR: SOO-MOOK MOON

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

 $\underline{\textit{ShadowTutor}}; \ \textbf{Knowledge distillation from the server to the edge device reduced network data transfer by 95\% and increased throughput by 3x. } \\$

OCTOBER 30, 2024 JAE-WON CHUNG

ADVISOR: KYOUNG MU LEE Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

• Designed improved meta-initialization methods for Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) with neural memory modules and convex programs.

Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping (QSM) with Deep Learning

Lab of Imaging Science and Technology, SNU

ADVISOR: JONGHO LEE

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Created a deep learning pipeline for QSM, a 3D MRI medical imaging task, including preprocessing, augmentation, and modeling (CAD-QSMNet).

Technical Skills

- Programming language proficiency, Python (typing, sync and async), Rust (sync and async), Go, CUDA, C++, Zig, Verilog, Shell scripting
- · Library/Framework familiarity, PyTorch, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, FastAPI, Pydantic, SQLAlchemy, Serde
- Tool familiarity, Docker, Kubernetes, KubeFlow, Elasticsearch, Fluent Bit, Prometheus, Jaeger, OpenTelemetry, LaTeX
- **Deep Learning systems optimization,** Experience in running and optimizing LLM training and inference serving. Small to medium code contributions to Text Generation Inference, vLLM, FastChat, TorchTitan, and DeepSpeed.
- **Deep Learning inference server deployment,** Publicly deployed an LLM chat service (The ML.ENERGY Colosseum) that can multiplex requests to multiple Text Generation Inference servers behind a NGINX reverse proxy. Contributed to Gradio in the process.
- **Deep Learning and Computer Vision**, Experience in identifying and formulating deep learning problems and building up the data processing, training, and evaluation pipeline, including few-shot image classification, meta-learning, and medical imaging (MRI).

Open Source Projects _____

- <u>BERT4Rec-VAE-Pytorch</u> (☆353 № 84), <u>A PyTorch framework for recommendation model training</u>, with abstract classes for pluggable model, dataset, and samplers. BERT4Rec and Netflix VAE models implemented.
- Zeus (\$\frac{207}{P}\$ 25), A framework for deep learning energy measurement and optimization. PyTorch ecosystem project. Constantly leading a team of student contributors. Integrates best practices such as full type-annotation, auto-generated source code reference, Docker, Pytest, and examples.
- Reason (\$\frac{190}{p}\$' 5), A shell for managing research papers, written in Rust. Supports importing papers from file and URL, attaching markdown notes, and creating an HTML book with notes. Uses serde to persist data in human-readable and cloud sync-friendly format.
- <u>Pegasus</u> (公31岁3), <u>An SSH command runner with a focus on simplicity, written in Rust.</u> Runs multiple commands asynchronously using the tokio runtime and streams stdout and stderr back to the user. Battle-tested through multiple research projects and benchmarking.

Number of stars and forks are up-to-date as of October 30th, 2024.

Honors & Awards

Nov 2022 Carbon Hack '22 Second Best Solution, Carbon-Aware DNN Training with Zeus, \$25,000

Green Software Foundation

Jul 2021 Kwanjeong Overseas Scholarship, \$25,000

Mar 2019 Kwanjeong Undergraduate Scholarship, \$20,000 over two years

Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Kwanjeong Educational Foundation

Grants & Funding

Jan 2024 **Research grant**, \$20,000 for the development of the ML.ENERGY Initiative

Salesforce

Jan 2024 Mozilla Technology Fund 2024, \$50,000 for the development of the Zeus project

Mozilla

Invited Talks

Apr 2024 Power and Energy Considerations in Machine Learning Systems

University of Michigan (EECS 598)

Oct 2023 Energy-Efficient Software Systems for Machine Learning
Oct 2023 Energy-Efficient Deep Learning with PyTorch and Zeus

Seoul National University

PyTorch Conference

Sep 2023 Energy-Efficient Deep Learning with Zeus

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Service_

• Systems/Software Reading Group, Paper reading group inside Michigan CSE, Organizer since Fall 2022

OCTOBER 30, 2024 JAE-WON CHUNG

Teaching

- Operating Systems (SNU, Spring 21), Lead TA, Managed Linux kernel hacking projects and led student team design reviews.
- Computer Architecture (SNU, Fall 20), Peer tutor, Provided 30 hours of online lecture, Best Tutor Award!

Mentorship _____

- ullet Luoxi Meng, Zeus open-source development, co-author of Perseus. Master's at UMich o PhD at UCSD
- Yile Gu, Co-author of Perseus. Master's at UMich \rightarrow PhD at UW
- ullet **Zhenning Yang**, Lead author of Chase, CarbonHack '22 second place award. Master's at UMich o PhD at UMich
- Yong Seung Lee, Zeus open-source development. Master's at UMich ightarrow Bloomberg
- Yuxuan Xia, ML.ENERGY Leaderboard contribution, Diffuserve. Master's at UMich.
- Oh Jun Kweon, ML.ENERGY Leaderboard contribution, Zeus open-source development. Master's at UMich.
- Parth Raut, Zeus open-source development. Master's at UMich.
- Wonbin Jin, Zeus open-source development. Bachelor's at UMich.
- Daniel Hou, Diffuserve. Zeus open-source development. Master's at UMich.
- Sharon Han, Zeus open-source development. Bachelor's at UMich.